novastor.com 2018-12-16

# Privacy Policy | NovaStor

Last modified: 5/24/2018

### NovaStor is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement applies to data collected by NovaStor through its websites and product registration.

1\. What This Privacy Policy Covers 2\. Control of Your Personal Information 3\. Types and Uses of Information We Collect 4\. Disclosure of Personal Information 5\. International Transfer of Information 6\. Changes in this Privacy Policy 

#### 

1\. What This Privacy Policy Covers

NovaStor takes the privacy and protection of personal information (“Personal Information”) very seriously. By visiting and using the Novastor websites, you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

This privacy policy describes NovaStor’s data collection, processing, and use of personal information and anonymous information collected when you visit or use any of our NovaStor owned websites or complete a product registration. 

#### 

2\. Control of Your Personal Information

##### Reviewing, Correcting and Removing Your Personal Information

You have the following data protection rights:

  * • You can request access, correction, updates or deletions of your personal information.
  * • You can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information.
  * • If we have collected and process your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * • You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information.

To exercise any of these rights, please contact us at [privacy@novastor.com](mailto:privacy@novastor.com) or by mail at NovaStor Corporation, 29209 Canwood Street, Agoura Hills, CA 91301 USA, Attention: Privacy. We will respond to your request to change, correct or delete your information within a reasonable timeframe and notify you of the action we have taken.

##### Controlling Unsolicited Email ("Spam")

NovaStor is concerned about controlling unsolicited commercial email, or "spam." NovaStor will not sell, lease, or rent its email subscriber lists to third parties. NovaStor has taken precautions to ensure that unsolicited commercial marketing emails are not sent. We also require the inclusion of an opt-out mechanism and other required information to be included in every email sent through our marketing platform. 

##### Unsubscribing from Our Communications

You may unsubscribe from our marketing communications by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link located on the bottom of our emails, updating your communication preferences, or by send us an email at [privacy@novastor.com](mailto:privacy@novastor.com) or postal mail to NovaStor Corporation, 29209 Canwood Street, Agoura Hills, CA 91301 USA, Attention: Privacy. Customers cannot opt-out of receiving transactional emails related to their products or subscription service with us.

#### 

3\. Types and Use of Information We Collect

Our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you.

In general, information you submit to us is used by us to respond to requests that you make, to better tailor our messaging and support, and to offer you additional information, opportunities, and learning. We also use this information to enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf. We may create Anonymous Information records from Personal Information by excluding information that makes the information personally identifiable to you. 

Here are the types of information we collect: 

##### "Personal Information"

Personal information is information that is personally identifiable like names, addresses, or phone numbers, as well as other non-public information that is associated with the foregoing.

We collect the following Personal Information that you submit to us voluntarily:

  * • Upon accessing our websites, certain usage information is automatically collected and then saved. This information that can directly or indirectly identify an individual includes, among other things, your Internet Protocol (IP) address and geographical location.
  * • If you fill out any of the forms on our websites, we collect any Personal Information you may provide, including but not limited to, your name, company, country, email address, phone number the details of your request or any other information you choose to provide.
  * • When you contact us by email, chat or phone, we may collect Personal Information you provide us voluntarily in connection with this communication.
  * • Personal Information can also include transactions that you enter on the website, and information about you that is available on the internet, such as from Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, Google, or publicly available information that we acquire from service providers.
  * • If you give us credit card information, we use it solely to check your financial qualifications and collect payment from you. We use a third-party service provider to manage credit card processing for all online orders. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use information you provide except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf. For direct purchases, as in the case with larger business accounts, we will ask for purchasing information directly, such as your credit card number and billing address, which will be used to create a NovaStor billing account. Except for this, we do not collect Sensitive Information from you.

##### “Automatic Data Collection and Anonymous Information”

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. This automatic exchange of data between your browser and our server upon accessing our pages informs us of data like which browser you are using, your referral source, date and length of visit and pages viewed.

The information we collect automatically is called “Anonymous Information.” Anonymous Information means information that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Information. Thus, Anonymous Information does not permit the identification of individual persons.

We may use this Anonymous Information for internal purposes, such as maintaining our operating ability, preventing fraudulent access to our websites or analyzing usage patterns so that we may enhance our websites. We also reserve the right to use and disclose any Anonymous Information at our discretion, although you will remain anonymous as an individual user.

We automatically collect information through different technologies as described below.

##### Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

Our website uses technologies such as Cookies, web beacons, tags and scripts. These technologies are used to analyze trends, administer the websites, track users’ movements around the websites and to gather demographic information about our user-base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by their respective providers on an aggregated basis.

###### Use of Cookies

NovaStor websites use "cookies" to help personalize your online experience. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies contain information that can later be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to store your preferences and other information on your computer in order to save you time by eliminating the need to repeatedly enter the same information and to display your personalized content on your later visits to these sites. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. In addition, you can delete Cookies that have already been saved on your computer at any time.

###### Use of Web Beacons

NovaStor websites may contain electronic images known as web beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs - that may be used to assist in delivering cookies on our sites and allow us to count users who have visited those pages. We may include web beacons in promotional email messages or our newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. NovaStor may also employ web beacons from third parties in order to help us compile aggregated statistics regarding the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns or other operations of our sites. We prohibit web beacons on our sites from being used by third parties to collect or access your personal information.

When you receive newsletters or promotional email from NovaStor, we may use web beacons, customized links or similar technologies to determine whether the email has been opened and which links you click in order to provide you more focused email communications or other information. 

###### Google Analytics

Our website may use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google uses Cookies to help analyze the use of our websites. On behalf of NovaStor, Google Analytics uses cookies to examine your interaction with NovaStor websites. 

Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the Site, compile reports on Site activity and provide other Site activity and internet related services. In addition, Google may also transfer this information to third parties if required by law or if third parties process the information on Google’s behalf.

By using NovaStor websites, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described and for the aforementioned purpose. More information about Google Analytics can be found [](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html)here.

###### Advertising and Partnerships

We partner with a third-party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, and you are located in the European Union, go [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

From time to time, we may receive Personal Information about you from third party sources including partners with which we offer co-branded services or engage in joint marketing activities, and publicly available sources such as social media websites.

We may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, we do not transfer your Personal Information to the third party.

##### Security of Your Personal Information

NovaStor is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We secure the Personal Information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. All Personal Information is protected using appropriate physical, technical and organizational measures. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. Also, we recommend that you do not save your password in a so-called password manager. 

##### Privacy of Minors

Our websites are not intended for or targeted at children under 16, and we do not knowingly or intentionally collect information about children under 16. If you believe that we have collected information about a child under 16, please contact us at privacy@novastor.com, so that we may delete the information.

#### 

4\. Disclosure of Personal Information

Except as described in this statement, we will not disclose your personal information outside of NovaStor and its controlled subsidiaries and affiliates without your consent. 

We reserve the right to provide your personal information to NovaStor distribution partners solely in order to allow them to offer advice and/or sell NovaStor products and services. Our distribution partners are prohibited from using your personal information unless the use is directly related to NovaStor. 

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support, hosting websites, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. Those service providers will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose. 

We may access or disclose information about you, including the content of your communications, in order to: (a) comply with the law or respond to lawful requests or legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of NovaStor or our customers, including the enforcement of our agreements or policies governing your use of the services; or (c) act on a good faith belief that such access or disclosure is necessary to protect the personal safety of NovaStor employees, customers or the public. 

#### 

5\. International Transfer of Information

Personal information collected on NovaStor sites and services may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which NovaStor or its affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities. By using our web site or a NovaStor service, you agree that your personal information may be transferred to any country in which NovaStor or its affiliates, subsidiaries or distribution partners maintain facilities. 

#### 

6\. Changes in this Privacy Policy

We will occasionally update this privacy statement to reflect changes in our services or based on customer feedback. When we post changes to this Statement, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of this statement. If there are material changes to this statement or in how NovaStor will use your personal information, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this statement to be informed of how NovaStor is protecting your information. 

##### Enforcement of This Privacy Statement

If you have questions regarding this statement, you should first contact us.

##### Contacting Us

NovaStor welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement. If you have questions about this statement or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us. 

For further Information on NovaStor offices, please go to our contact page.
